I made 4,562 Instagram posts, and this is
what I've learned.
I started my Instagram page on November
the 11th, 2016.
That is 2,913 days ago, and I suppose
that averages
1.57 posts a day, every day,
for seven years
and 11 months. That's pretty insane,
right?
Well, in that time,
I've grown my audience to around 1.4
million people, and it
took me four years of posting on social
media to even reach 10,000.
It then took me another four years to
reach one million followers.
My top three short-form content platforms
have 4.3 million followers,
and in growing all of these,
I've learned 32 lessons.
So let's get into it.
Lesson number one,
hashtags don't do anything.
The chap on Instagram called Mosseri,
who is the CEO of Instagram, came out and
quite frankly said it,
they don't do anything.
Whenever I see people copy-paste hashtags,
a little bit of me feels sad inside,
that someone out there in the notes
section of their phone has populated a
load of
hashtags, and they feel that
if they paste that into the description
or to the
comments of their post,
that it will bring them more engagement.
I've said for years,
not only does it make you look desperate,
it looks shit.
Maybe a long time ago, content
was sorted and categorized into hashtags,
but it's
2024. Rest assured
that every single word
and item you put in a video is going
to be scanned and audited by the platform.
This is to ensure it has some idea of what
the video's about.
If the platform didn't do this,
how do you think it could curate the
content you
like so well and put it onto your feed?
Hashtags need to go.
They need to stop being used.
If you want people to discover your
content, make it
better.
Don't post loads of random words in a
description hoping for the best.
Only use hashtags when bantering,
like #teamnochest or
#teamnosleep, #thickthighssavelives.
But I tell you what,
be careful with the last one.
I actually own the trademark for thick
thighs save lives,
and I'm just waiting for
some fitness twat to try whack it on a
T-shirt, and I'll take them to court.
And this brings me onto the next lesson,
originality at your peril.
Originality. Einstein famously said,
"Standing on the shoulders of giants,"
which is, well, it's cool, but in essence,
your job on a day-to-day basis is to
look at the landscape and see what
is working. Think about investors.
They don't just buy into shit
that doesn't work and hope for the best.
They look at trends
and try to jump on them,
and we must do the same.
Truth be told,
I like to talk to my sensei, Ed,
from the page Creative Booth, and
we talk about many things.
And he said his last video was doing well.
So when I was watching it,
I couldn't help but think about the
incredible packaging
that he used for it. He then told me
that he came up with this video due to the
reaction he got from other mediums,
like emails and modules.
So in essence,
Ed had already done a lot of work for me.
So this video, although the title
is the same, I didn't steal it.
Technically, I hired him. And don't worry,
I paid him more than what it costs me to
pay my mortgage for seven months,
so he doesn't mind. A bit like you.
If you rip off my content,
you're a grade A bellend.
But if you join one of my various courses,
you're merely a student doing what
you've been told.
There's a bit of classic manipulation.
Where were we?
Oh, well, so I saw Ed's title
and thumbnail, and I thought, "That
is really good.
I will make my own version." I will also
pay homage to where I got it from.
It's like referencing someone in a study
when you use a bit of content, which is a
good thing to do in content.
So let's maybe call that unit 2A,
reference evidence,
and it'll make you look smarter.
If you just reference where you got the
information,
it'll make you seem more genuine.
So I saw what was working with Ed,
and I thought I could make my own version
because Instagram, short-form content,
which this is about, I could potentially
give more value than Ed could.
He's the expert in YouTube.
I suppose I'm a kind of an expert in
Instagram.
Now, at the moment,
I work with hundreds of creators,
and I see them trying to make
their own type of viral content,
and more than often it flops.
Whereas if they'd just seen what had
worked for other people, they could have
emulated perhaps the prop or the hook
or the setting, even the scene,
and then they
could have gone off in their own
direction.
You need to see what is working
and jump on that.
I'm not entirely sure how sailboats worked
for all those years.
Do you ever wonder how people got around
the world on boats?
I assume they knew
which way the currents and the winds
were going, and they just
kind of hopped on those.
Seems a bit risky and mad
if you think about it, but it'd
be very daft to just guess your way across
the Pacific Ocean, wouldn't it?
So maybe don't do
that next time you're in the process of
planning and strategizing
where you want your content to go.
I've seen some creators recycle the same
hook
dozens of times. And actually,
Ryan Trahan, MrBeast,
some of the biggest YouTubers
have straight up ripped titles
and thumbnails off other creators.
And you ask why?
Because it works.
And something working will always trump
something
original. China. China.
Which brings me onto lesson number two.
It's technically lesson number three,
but I'm one behind.
My favorite lesson, my favorite lesson,
the best lesson, trends.
They change, so keep an eye on them.
Suddenly scrolling across social media
isn't just wasting time, babe.
I'm researching, babe.
I'm staying on top of things.
I'm researching things, many things,
and the top creators on social media will
show
you many patterns. I saw Sean Casey
was getting some mad engagement on
carousels,
so I took note, did some myself,
and they did very well.
And why carousels do well,
I'll explain later.
But when you see trends like I did,
where the people that end their stories go
blank for 24 hours,
so then they can post another one with an
offer and it gets
more views,
or just the setups they're using in their
content, keep an eye on it
because this is an ever-changing
landscape. Try things out.
And remember, if a post bombs,
no one's going to see it.
Because no one sees it,
there's nothing to worry about.
You can always unlist it
and further down the line, even delete it.
Your worst posts will get the least views
most of the time.
So I noticed a trend recently about super
long videos on YouTube.
Matt Armstrong, who does the cars,
he has a Mark II channel,
and he's uploading
videos that are four hours long.
The average view duration on these videos
is
crushing the algorithm.
So I notice trends like that,
get my notepad out, think
about average view duration scoring well,
and I do my best to, I don't know, make
longer videos,
like one assimilating 30-odd of the best
things that I've learnt
whilst I'm teaching you about identifying
trends and jumping on them whilst also
trying to jump on a trend myself to see
how it does.
We are all to be our very best own
scientists, and we must test
and trial things to
see how they do, which
is what I'm doing whilst you're learning
about it.
Which brings me onto number four, camera.
You can do a lot on an iPhone.
In fact,
I grew my social media following on
Facebook to 50,000 followers just
going live on an iPhone. Truth be told,
I didn't know how to edit,
which I'll cover
in one of the lessons coming up.
But an iPhone is great, and it
is great enough,
but you must level up with the times.
Every time there has been an opportunity
to level up, I take it.
Even these videos the last few weeks,
I've taken it to the next level.
In my mind,
it should correlate with your cash
position.
If you make £10,000 a month, come on, bro,
level up the iPhone.
When I hit a million dollars in revenue
from my last venture, I decided, come on,
I
need something a bit more than a $999
camera, which was the ZV-E10,
and now I've swapped it out because of the
autofocus issue for this FX3.
But you do not need a $4,000 camera.
In the future, you might.
But every video is its own little
production.
I even blacked out this room for this
production today because I want this to be
the best experience possible, but this
is the icing on the cake.
I don't think cameras are everything,
but they're a lot.
And if you're going to spend money going
to the cinema, you want the film crew to
use the best equipment because at the end
of the day, you're giving up your time to
enjoy it.
Which has made me paranoid we're not
recording.
Yeah, we're recording audio.
Thank God for that.
You'll know when it's time to level up,
and you can always just go to a camera
shop. They'll help.
You can get a secondhand camera
and a secondhand lens.
And basically, here's the take-home.
Give a shit about your content production
because it's hard to get people online to
give a shit about you
if you don't go to the effort for them.
Remember, all this content is for them.
When it comes to production,
we need to get into another little lesson,
which I
suppose would be lesson five.
Can you guys hear me all right in this
video?
Can you?
Of course you can because lesson five
is audio.
Audio is maybe sometimes more important
than visuals, I think, because sometimes
people listen more than they watch.
Whether podcasts, YouTube, or short-form.
You'll notice I don't have
that many interactions with all of this
content because
I want you to listen to what I'm saying
more so than anything else.
Shitty audio is a fast way to get people
to switch off.
People are much pickier with their audio
than they let slip. Think about this.
If someone's a noisy chewer of food
It makes you want to knock them the fuck
out.
So when your audio hisses
or sounds shitty,
it's just disrespectful to the
experience of the person watching
or listening.
Here, I'm using the Joe Rogan microphone.
So this is a Shure SM7B,
and it's a great microphone,
but it needs power, so I have
it connected to a Rodecaster. Now,
quick lesson.
This mic needs something called a
Cloudlifter to make it sound better.
This device that you can add gives it
clean gain.
So I had to originally buy a Cloudlifter.
However, times have changed.
When it comes to audio interface,
I use a Rodecaster II, which has a
Cloudlifter built in, which
is great because it makes the audio
that much better.
But Shure went one ahead recently,
and they built a Cloudlifter into their
latest
microphone, which is called a Shure SM7dB.
And you can tell
that I geek out on this stuff,
and you might wonder why.
It's because I fucking care about my
production.
I even got another bookshelf for
symmetricality.
In fact, I reached out to Ed, my sensei,
yesterday and asked him if he was using a
Cloudlifter because I could tell he
wasn't.
He inputs his Shure SM7B straight into his
camera, and you can slightly hear a hiss
in the sound floor
if you turn it up loud enough.
And most people don't care about this
stuff, but I care.
And I think games are won in the top 1%,
so for me, sound and a few hundred dollars
matter. For the majority of you,
get a DJI mic. They're the best.
And I've used Rode
and I've used DJI in every single way.
The DJI mic is enough to get you to the
point that in the future when you want to
get a Shure SM7B.
When it comes to cost-cutting, audio
is not one of those places.
You may think you can get away with shitty
audio, but trust me, you're not that
guy, pal. You're not that guy.
Which brings me on to lesson number six,
jump cuts. This video, you'll notice,
has all the gaps cut,
but we still let the words breathe,
but we cut all the crap
that you don't need.
Why? For you, well,
I don't want you to sit here
or watch here for any longer than
you need. Referring back to audio,
you do not want to hear me breathe.
ASMR noises weird people out. Also,
I want to be as succinct as possible.
I want to cut the crap.
But don't cut them too far.
You still need to let the words breathe.
I actually teach all of these lessons,
by the way, in my Content Mastery course,
and it's currently 99 US dollars,
and I'll leave a link in the description
below,
but let's get back into it.
Before we get into that,
let's get into lesson number
seven, the peril of using a videographer.
One must direct the direction of videos.
Sometimes you can hire people,
and they are great at what they do.
But Christopher Nolan,
when directing a film,
needs the best videographers and
camera people, but that doesn't mean
that they have the final say over how the
film
looks. I hired videographers for years,
and they made nice-looking videos, and I
put them online, and they'd fucking bomb.
And I always wondered why videographers
making shit look nice.
And I always wondered why.
Videographers make shit look nice,
but that is not
making great content. Great content
and nice-looking videos are miles apart.
You cannot hire someone to hold a camera
and expect them to make the magic happen
for you.
I've even seen friends of mine hire
members of staff, and the issue is
that they can offload the important
thinking and ideation to people on
salaries.
They often create subpar results.
If your business is going to have a
million-dollar idea or a video,
it's probably
going to come out of your mind,
not someone else's.
So hire people to work for you,
but not to do your job for you.
No one cares as much as you do.
No one ever will.
It's on you, so don't be fucking lazy.
Don't be fucking lazy.
China, China. Lesson number eight, hooks.
There are several types of hooks
that you can use in social media,
and you use them
to capture attention,
each with its own style and purpose.
So here are some of the most effective
ones.
So you could use a hook that shock
and surprises people,
and these hooks can catch
people off guard with an unexpected fact
or visual.
For example,
opening with a surprising statistic
or a bold statement.
What if I told you
that most fat loss diets
are more harm than good?
Then we could always ask a question hook,
and this, what we're looking to do is ask
a question at the beginning to encourage
engagement by making viewers think and to
respond. We then have a relatable
or a problem-solving hook, and
you can start this by addressing a common
problem, making the viewer feel seen and
understood.
Struggling to stay motivated to work out?
Here's what actually works.
These aren't too lumbersome or too long.
They're very short and succinct,
and they're something
that we can get out in the
first three to five seconds. Again,
we might have a value-driven hook.
This type promises a solution or a tip
or an insight that's immediately
beneficial,
like a how-to or a quick tip. Here
are three ways to boost your fat loss
without
changing your diet.
The next could be a curiosity hook,
which teases the content
without giving everything away,
prompting viewers to stick around to learn
more.
The one exercise
that you should never skip,
and you'll be surprised.
Another one we could do would be maybe a
shock reveal or a myth-busting hook.
And you can open with a controversial
or even a surprising statement
that debunks
common myths.
You don't need to be doing a lot of cardio
to lose fat, and this is
why.
Other things we could do would be a
personal story or a vulnerable
hook where you open with a short personal
anecdote or insight that can humanize
you, and it can help you build trust.
I used to hate going to the gym,
but this is what changed it for me.
What else?
We could also do a challenge
or a call to action hook.
And with this,
you could directly challenge the viewer to
do something or make a
decision.
If you're not seeing any benefits to your
cardio, try doing this.
jujitsu sparring ability, then try this
over the next 22 days.
We could then have a demonstration
or a visual hook, and you
can begin with the demonstration of a
product, an exercise, a technique, and you
can show value immediately.
Starting a video with you performing a
workout move,
that's crucial for getting a contraction
or enlisting an outcome.
Another one I would use is humor
or an unexpected twist hook.
So you could use humor, irony,
or a twist to grab attention
and entertain right
from the start.
And then another one would be maybe a
countdown or a list hook
where you start with a countdown
or top tips or a list structure
and keep people
watching for each point.
You might even have a visual whiteboard
behind you.
These are five ways to grow your
entrepreneurial business to 100K within
the next
one year. The benefit of this
is by using different types of hooks,
we can keep our
audience engaged and cater to a range of
viewer preferences.
And this is super important in the early
stages of content creation.
Your first five seconds are so important.
Do not take it lightly how important they
are.
If you can get your hook right,
the rest is easy.
However, keep in mind for longer format,
you may want to have an introduction, and
this can have some hooks in it. But
if someone is watching a YouTube video
like
this one,
I may need to pay off the title
and thumbnail with more priority than a
traditional hook to let the viewer know
they're making the right decision.
Like I did in this one,
I kind of repeated the title,
then gave the authority
that it's one and a half posts a day.
People go, "Wow, that's a lot.
This guy must know a lot about this." Then
we get into the lessons.
And talking of lessons,
we should probably get into lesson number
eight, call to
actions and goodwill.
Do you remember "Fast
and the Furious One?" Rest in peace,
Paul Walker. In the first drag race,
Paul Walker uses his NOS way too fast.
This is why he loses to our Vin Diesel,
and this is what you should do when it
comes to your call to actions.
Do not shoot your load too soon.
We must accrue goodwill from your
audience.
And if I'm honest on this channel,
I'm fucking prepared to post on this
channel for
one to two years before it booms.
I know human beings, and some of you
are ready,
but most of you are not,
and I will use this as fuel to keep me
going more than
anything.
I will wear you down across months
and years if I need to.
I know I cannot just expect to pull the
NOS because I hit 10,000 subscribers
on this. Thank you, by the way,
but I will leave a subtle call to actions
in my
description, but that's it. That is it.
I'm willing to go to town for years
if I need to.
So with your short-form content, get in,
get out, be classy. Don't ask for follows.
Occasionally give a call to action,
maybe for a resource or something
that helps
them. But for most of you,
you're a lot of posts away from doing the
work necessary
to actually have the leverage to get
people to actually do it.
I want you to be willing to see social
media as a place you literally help people
for free for years,
and you need to be okay with people not
signing up.
I created my Facebook account on the 1st
of April 2014.
I have people come up to me
and say how much I've helped them lose 20
kilograms,
and then they say,
"I never joined your program,
but you helped me so much."
What, you never gave me your money?
Cheers.
But you need to be okay with that,
because if you can't help people for free,
then
you won't get people to join for money.
There's a real slim line between helping
people for free and having loads of
clients.
So don't leave things on the table.
Give people as much as you can.
Give them so much
that they get suspicious
that maybe you were sent from above to
come here from heaven to help them.
When you can do that for long enough,
people will respond to your call to
actions.
But until then, keep pumping,
keep hustling, and be sparing with
call to actions or you look, well,
a little bit beggy and we
don't want that.
Which brings me on to lesson nine,
purpose.
Your purpose on social media
is to help them, not you.
A lot of creators get caught up in the
world of me, me, me when it needs to be
about them, them, them.
Here's my breakfast becomes, If you are
looking for an amazing breakfast you can
have every day, then I would recommend the
exact same breakfast that I
was going to talk about before.
In the world of content creation,
we become subservient to those who
subscribe and
watch our content. It sounds weird,
but the faster you realize
that your purpose is
to help strangers on the internet,
the better you can come to the reality of
it.
I like to personally go a bit further.
I like to make it feel like I'm their
mate.
I overshare. I'm brutally honest, too.
And my approach is to the point that
if I bump into someone, perhaps even you,
I
want you to feel like I'm your mate
that you haven't met yet.
And really,
the only time you should talk about
yourself is when it can directly
help them. If you want to help yourself,
help other people.
Smith J. 2024. Lesson 10.
Is it 10 lessons?
I have no idea at this point.
Let's talk about frequency.
How often should you post? Well,
I think it's a good idea to aim for at
least
daily. Not that there's even
that much in it beyond the fact
that you need to do
the fucking reps to get better at it.
But if you want to become great at
something, do it daily.
It doesn't have to be a full-on
production, but fuck me, on a slow day,
you could
screenshot a tweet
and post it on your Instagram.
It doesn't have to be a full-blown
cameras, lighting, production, scripting,
whatever. In my opinion,
you cannot post too often.
It can only be too boring.
I'll repeat that again.
You cannot post too often.
It can only be too boring.
Maybe one more time.
You cannot post too often.
You can only be too boring.
Which I suppose then brings me on to
lesson 11,
which kind of ties into this one a bit,
reposts.
The majority of my videos go viral the
second or third time I post it.
For many of you in the early onset of
content creation, imagine this.
Create a new piece of content,
take an old piece, and post it again.
You double your posting frequency for not
a lot more work, maybe a minute more work
going back and finding it on your iPhone.
The beauty of this
is not everyone saw your first post.
Now some people are going to go,
"I've already seen this post,"
but the people that
moan and go,
"I'm going to unfollow you because you
posted a post more than once."
"Friends" has been on TV for like 30
years. No one's complaining.
You don't see "Friends" on TV going, "Oh,
Chandler and Monica, I've seen it, man."
Oh, you know,
they just put it on because someone might
want to watch it.
And the people that get annoyed
that you've reposted something
are not the people
that buy your product the day it comes
out.
Because the people that
are your best clients go,
"Do you know what, James?
I'm glad you posted it again because I
loved that video the first time I watched
it. And do you know what?
The second time I watched it, I liked it,
too." Because
sometimes we need to be reminded more than
we need to be taught.
Sometimes people double tap that thing
and share it to their story, not because
they've watched it again,
but they know how it made them feel the
first time, and
they want other people to see it,
and they will champion you
and help you grow
your-- Just repost. Repost.
You don't put two, three hours
into something to just leave it there
once, especially in short form.
In YouTube,
can you get away with it as much?
Probably not.
But in short form, especially
if you're growing on social media,
whenever anyone
gives me any shit, I'm like, "Sorry mate,
I've grown by 137,000
followers since I last posted this,
so I just put this up there so an audience
the
size of people at Twickenham
when it sold out could watch it." Next
thing I want to
talk about is lighting. Face the light.
So those of you that are filming at home,
if you can face natural light, the
better. For this today, for this camera,
this lens, I've actually blacked it out,
and I've got a professional light here.
This still isn't the perfect lighting
setup because I need to get something for
my
camera called an ND filter. But again,
we are getting carried away.
In essence, because of the way
that I'm filming now, an ND filter is like
sunglasses for your camera,
which lets less light in,
which can have a beneficial
appeal to blurring out the background.
But again,
that's probably a bit too advanced for
most people.
But lighting, stage one,
face natural lighting.
Do not have lights on above you
or down lighting or anything behind.
It just distorts everything.
All the lights off in the room face
natural lighting.
Again, this is flat lighting.
If the light was to my side,
it would be more of a
Rembrandt. For the majority of you,
just become well lit.
The background does not need to be well
lit.
There is a glow light,
and I will get some more. But lesson 12,
lighting.
Just face the bloody light
and turn them top lights off because most
lights in the
house are the orangey glows
that makes you look ridiculous.
What would be another lesson?
Lesson 13 would be time to post.
Now,
I don't think there's quite the importance
on the time to post that everyone
else says there is.
I think it's maybe smart
that you don't post when the majority
of your audience are asleep,
and maybe do post an hour
or two hours before you
think that peak time
is to let the post get a bit of traction
on social media, but
ultimately get it out at a sensible time.
Don't wait till 3:00 in the morning to put
it out.
But again,
some people even say don't post at 8:00
AM.
Post at 7:55 because all the other
creators are posting at 8:00.
Look,
the algorithm's working all around the
clock to make sure if you've done a
real banger of a video
and someone could benefit from it,
it's going to put it
together,
so don't worry about it too much.
Lesson 13, just did it.
Lesson 14 Spreading your seeds.
And what I mean by this isn't shagging
people
unprotected and getting spunk in them.
What I'm saying is,
if you're going to make an asset for
Instagram, get it out on
Facebook, get it out on TikTok,
get it out on Twitter,
get it out on LinkedIn, get
it out on YouTube Shorts if you can.
If you've made the asset,
get it everywhere.
Get it everywhere because the majority of
the work has gone into making that reel.
Put it everywhere you can,
even on Threads. Is anyone using Threads?
I don't know, but all you need
is one post to blow up,
and you could have 10 more
clients,
which for a lot of you could mean a lot
more business for what?
Taking a post somewhere.
Spread your seeds everywhere you can.
It just seems crazy to me
that some people would go to so much work
to put-- I'm
going to repurpose clips from this video
for my Instagram. Anywhere I can.
I want this everywhere.
Why do we spread our seeds?
So we can harvest and make loads of money.
Next thing would be rule of thirds.
You should notice
that on this screen here, my eye line
is pretty much
on that top third.
So we've got a third here,
we've got a third here.
And we do not want my eye line down in the
middle.
We want it perfectly in the right place.
So that's something to keep in mind
when you're filming portrait as well.
We don't want too much dead space.
We do not want our eye line in the middle.
If you type in rule of thirds into YouTube
or even, I'm going to get Declan
editing this to show you the grid of a
rule of thirds on a portrait and a
landscape,
just so you guys can see what the rule of
thirds looks like.
Just make sure you're in the right place
because this makes it look good and
appealing and appeasing for people.
And if you can nail that
and just make sure you don't have too much
dead space in
the wrong places,
it will make your content look good.
For this one, even
if I am slightly out of dimensions,
I know that my videographer,
Declan,
will clip this into size to make it look
good.
Lesson 16 would be scripting.
So the first five, 10 minutes of this
video I scripted. Yes, I scripted,
which is very naughty.
You naughty, naughty. You're teasing me.
And even I've read the first part from a
teleprompter.
I'm now free-balling it on the second one.
But for me, with a video like this,
that can have a really big impact to a
colder
audience because I already know the
packaging is going to work on it because I
copied it from Ed. I thought it
was worth spending two hours this morning
to script
the first part of the video to make sure
that the first part of the video is where
everyone's going to think about leaving.
I need to put more effort into that.
When I got to lesson 16 to 30,
I knew these ones off the top of my head.
But the first ones, it
was really important that the flow
was good, everything else
was good, so I scripted it.
If a piece of content is really important,
you'd be
crazy to leave it up to your mind to come
up with.
So don't be afraid to script things.
You can also just script something,
read it out, and cover it in B-roll, which
we'll get into in a second. Scripting
is an amazing tool that you can implement.
It gives you better flow.
It makes you sound smarter.
And getting a teleprompter for long form
content, anything over five minutes is
probably a good idea. Short form content,
you don't really need a teleprompter
because I believe you could just read from
something and cover it in B-roll.
However, doing this video,
covering it in B-roll would be just bloody
hard work.
Lesson 17, I would say,
would be eye level to make sure
that you have a camera
at eye level because we don't want huge
discrepancies of people looking down to
people, people looking up to people.
We want to make sure we're looking someone
in the eyes.
Any personal trainer watching this knows
that when your client's exercising on the
floor,
you get down onto your knee to make sure
you're not looking down to people.
Lesson 18 would be repetition.
The only way you get better at things
is to do it
more.
The only way you get better at things
is to do it more.
Whatever area you're lacking in,
whether it's scripting,
whether it's filming,
whether it's talking to camera,
whatever it is, if you do more at it,
you will get
better. There is nothing out there
that doesn't require huge amounts of
repetitions for mastery.
And the quicker you guys can just do the
repetitions, the
better. The more YouTube you do,
the better you're going to get at YouTube.
The more chin-ups you do,
the better you get at that.
Everything, repetition is the way.
For any of you not doing the thing
that you need to do,
I will remind you that the
lessons you need are in the tasks
that you're avoiding.
Now, lesson 19 would be B-roll. Now,
B-roll, in essence, is footage of
you doing the thing you're talking about.
So if I was to do a video on the deadlift,
I would probably script it and be like,
the most important part of the deadlift
is this, this, this.
Now,
as you go to put your hands on the bar,
I would after film my hands going onto
the bar.
I would say the important thing is
that your finger should be this far out
from the knurling.
I would then film my finger going
that far out from the
knurling. Then as we're doing the video,
rather than me trying to talk to the
camera the whole time,
we can just do footage
that goes over the top of it.
Any of you that have watched Ancient
Civilizations or what is it?
Ancient Apocalypse on Netflix.
If you watch it, you'll notice
that the A-roll is
Graham Hancock talking to camera.
The B-roll is drone footage,
people out and about,
everything like that.
He is reading a script.
If you actually watch Ancient Apocalypse,
the whole thing
is scripted with other footage put in
between.
But the B-roll makes such a good thing.
You can get stock B-roll online, but
if you can film your own B-roll,
it's going to
look so much better.
Another person you could look at online on
YouTube is Matt
D'Avella.
He is incredible at doing long amounts of
B-roll.
For me,
I just couldn't B-roll these videos.
That would be too much work.
But you'll notice
that in some of my short form content,
if you're talking about
something and you can visually film
that and overlay it, it just makes the
whole thing look so much better. A-roll
is your main track like this.
B-roll is anything
that comes over the top Lesson number 20,
stories.
Stories are the best things. Stories
are how you get people to go to war.
All religions are stories.
If you can tell a story, the better.
So if you're talking about fat loss
or something relatively boring,
tell a story.
I ate 50% calories for two weeks,
and this is what happened.
Because now we have a story,
and we have a hook.
I gave up carbs for a month, and this
is what-- I tried carnivore for a month,
and
this is what happened. A story,
a challenge. People
are interested in stories.
In this video,
we're going to look at how fat loss works.
Don't care.
In this video,
I'm going to show you what happened to me
when I didn't eat for 30
days,
and we're going to learn what you can do
in your life to make sure you can
lose fat without having to do what I did.
Oh, my God.
Tell stories the best you can.
Anytime you want views, tell stories.
If you don't have stories, make them up.
Do challenges, whatever it is.
Lesson 21, chatbots.
Meta will permit chatbots for Facebook and
Instagram.
They're powerful tools at the moment to
get people to comment certain
prompts. For instance,
if you DM me on Instagram content,
you'll get a bot
about content mastery.
If you DM me mentorship,
you'll get a message about joining
my mentorship.
We can then put out posts
that tell people for these prompts.
I have people using prompts for posts I
did weeks ago, and they're still getting
sent through DM automations that's getting
them to buy things.
So ManyChat is probably the best one.
ManyChat is incredible,
and it's made me a lot of money this year.
Lesson number 22, carousels.
If you put music on a carousel,
it will get shown
to a new audience.
It will be shown to that Reels feed.
But if you do it without music,
it will be shown to your current audience,
which I
actually think is better in some ways.
Now you get up to 20 photos on carousels.
So I think the videos and Reels
are your best way to grow your following,
grow your
brand, all of those.
But I think at every occasion,
you should be doing a 10 to 20
picture carousel, which should be a story,
but should also have a chatbot, and this
will be shown to your existing audience.
So if you can take them on an emotional
rollercoaster,
it's a very powerful tool to
use, so please use it. Lesson number 23,
you should always be pushing things to
Facebook, even if you don't use Facebook.
Set up a business account.
Pushing Reels to Facebook,
so many people I work with,
they start doing it.
A few weeks later, they go, "Oh, my God,
a Reel went viral on Facebook.
I didn't even know.
It grew my account by 10,000.
I wondered where those lead..." Make sure
you're putting stuff to Facebook.
I honestly think that I make,
or the last 10 years,
I've made more money from
Facebook than I did Instagram,
and I've always had a bigger Instagram
following.
So Facebook is still a weapon. There
are still people on it.
Do not sleep on it.
Lesson number 24, haters.
When your comments go to shit,
that's good news.
Your Reel has gone to a new audience.
When the algorithm's pushing your stuff,
you just get more and more hatred.
Instead of seeing hatred
and negativity as a bad thing,
it's a good thing.
It means your Reel is performing well.
If your Reel bombs, no one hates it.
People are always going to hate you.
They're always going to try to rip into
you.
You can block them.
Best thing you can do
is actually to restrict them, and
restricting them is great because they can
keep commenting, and they don't know
that no one else can see it.
So they're wasting their energy trying to
ruin your
day when really you're ruining their day
with an Uno Reverse +4.
People are always going to unfollow you.
My unfollow rate is massive.
So for every two followers I gain,
I lose one.
So if I look at my Instagram algorithms,
most of the time, it's like, "You gained
20,000 followers,
but you lost 10,000." Don't take it
personally.
It's just people are not interested.
They're going through a different stage of
life, whatever it is.
You cannot lose sleep about that.
You just can't.
How many of your friends from high school
do you not stay in touch with?
Are you bothered? No.
You go through phases of your life where
people are your
friends,
then they're not your friends anymore.
You don't give a fuck.
So don't give a fuck about random people
on the internet that once followed you and
then realized that you weren't their bag
of fish. Is that even a saying?
I don't know. Don't worry about it.
Don't lose sleep about it.
You only need 50 people to live a very
good life.
50 clients,
you probably borderline need to hire
someone.
So you don't need all these strangers on
the internet. Do not take it personally.
My next lesson would be about stop trying
to impress other people in the same line
of work as you.
If only I had a penny for personal
trainers that were trying to
impress other personal trainers with their
content, or they were worried about the
opinions of other personal trainers.
Other personal trainers
are the only people that
are never going to buy your
product. So me, as like a business guru,
if other business gurus
chirp in and go, "Oh,
you're an idiot," well, you
were never going to buy my
course, brother. You
were never going to buy it.
You were never going to contribute into my
life.
You were never going to do anything,
so I don't care.
If you own a butcher's
and you sell meat and kebabs,
don't worry about what vegans
say because they're never going to buy
your shit.
It's why I go in on bodybuilders
and vegans and CrossFitters.
I pretty much go in on the people that
are never going to buy my stuff.
You get engagement,
and you never have to worry about your
sales being impacted
because they're never going to buy anyway.
Lesson number 29, caffeine.
You should be well-caffeinated
when you do content.
And if you don't like caffeine,
be caffeinated.
And what I mean by that is bring it,
bit of aggression, bit of je ne sais quoi.
Bring that.
I thought je ne sais quoi meant something
special in French, and I
hired a videographer who I fired.
His name was Etienne. He was retarded.
And I remember we were in Dubai,
and I said to him, "Oi, Etienne,
what does je ne
sais quoi mean?" He goes,
"I don't know." I said,
"What do you mean you don't know,
brother?" I said, "You're fucking French.
At what level of idiot are you?" I said,
"Je ne sais quoi. What does it mean?
Because I've been saying you need a bit of
je ne sais quoi in your content." He
goes, "I don't know." I go, "Bro,
you're fucking French-Canadian.
How do you not know what je ne sais quoi
means?" He goes, "Eh, it means I don't
know." I went, "What?
Je ne sais quoi means I don't know?" Turns
out, I've been
saying,
"You need a little bit of I don't know in
your content," and yeah, I nearly
fucking--
He nearly lost his front teeth there.
Nearly gave him the left, right,
good night like that. Be caffeinated.
You can tell the caffeine's kicked in for
me. Number 30, play the long game.
People overestimate what they can do in
weeks,
and they underestimate what they can
do in years.
There's going to come points where you
become very frustrated.
You feel like giving up.
You feel almost depressed with the lack of
progress that
you're making. This
is where everyone else gives up, brother.
If you keep going at this point, this
is where you get ahead.
When you get to that point
that you're literally pulling your hair
out and you're
like, "Oh, my God,
I can't do this," just know, rest assured,
other people are giving up. And
if you can just keep pushing through that,
that is
how you play the long game.
Lesson number 31 would be resilient.
No, it's 30, not 31. Resilience.
You're going to have good days,
you're going to
have bad days,
you're going to have unfollows,
you're going to have shitty
comments. You cannot let it bother you.
It cannot bother your path.
You must stay resilient.
You're going to go through loads of
whirlwinds on the way
there. But if you can remain resilient
and push through and not care about all of
these things, you can make it to the top.
And I think my final lesson would be to
ensure that your sole purpose
of social media on there,
all this short-form content,
is to get people's email
addresses. It's not to make sales,
not to grow your following.
It's to get email addresses.
At the end of the day,
if you want me to cater and
judge the performance of your short-form
content, it is how many emails you are
getting. Now,
you're probably wondering why I went this
far through a video giving
all this information. It was one
that I wanted to help you guys with
understanding these different--
But the main thing
is I sell a course teaching
this,
and it's called Short-Form Content
Mastery, and there's a link in the
description. It's 99 US dollars.
And here's the best part.
If you did that and went through all the
modules and you're like, "There's a few
things missing," just message me in the
Discord and I'll add the module.
That's it.
I'm growing it as time goes on.
It's getting better week on week,
and it's 99 US
dollars, which is heinously cheap.
And if that hasn't tickled your pickle to
go do that, then YouTube will
probably, like it always does,
put a little video here
that it recommends.
And YouTube's a smart bugger, so
if it says you should watch that,
you should
probably watch that. Thanks for watching.